Hey, guys.
All:
Hey.
So... what do you think?
About what?
Yeah, what?
What?
Huh?
Are you kidding?
Okay, I'll give you a hint.
I'll give you a hint.
Eyes.
No, no. Your eyes.
No. Chandler's eyes!
I got glasses.
You-you always had glasses.
No, I didn't.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Didn't, didn't you
used to have a pair
that were really
round and burgundy
and they made you
look kind of, um...
Feminine.
Yes.
No.
Sweetie, I think
the glasses look great.
They make you look really sexy.
Really?
Yeah.
You didn't think
I used to wear glasses, right?
Of course.
( mouthing ):
I didn't know it.
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's D.O.A. ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ When the rain starts to pour ♪
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
♪ Like I've been there before ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
So, what do you guys want
for an engagement present?
That's okay, Pheebs.
We're not having
a party or anything
so you don't
have to get us...
Bup-bup-bup!
Someone wants
to give us a present
we don't want
to deprive them of that joy.
Oh, you know what
you should get them?
One of those little
portable CD players.
Oh, I already
have one.
Not unless someone borrowed it
and left it at the gynecologist.
Yeah, and-and by "someone,"
she means Joey.
Hey, I know what I want.
What we want, honey.
No, no, you don't want this.
No, I want to have
your grandmother's
cookie recipe.
You mean the chocolate chip
cookie recipe?
Uh-huh, yeah.
You mean the one
that my grandmother made me
swear on her deathbed
that I would never let out
of our family?
Dying people say
the craziest things.
I've wanted it for years.
I was going to make
cookies for my children.
Well, break my heart.
Oh, all right.
Okay. I'm going
to be the mom
who makes the world's best
chocolate chip cookies.
Our kids are going
to be fat, aren't they?
Ahoy!
All:
Hey.
How's the boat?
Great. I'm really getting into
this sailing stuff.
Oh, so you finally took it
out of the marina, huh?
Why would I do that?
It took three guys
to get the thing in there.
Well, if you don't sail your
boat, what do you do on it?
Well, it's great.
It's a great place
to just kind of sit,
hang around
drink a few beers,
eat some chips.
Well, it's good
that you finally have
a place to do that.
You know, Joey,
I could teach you
to sail if you want.
You could?
Yeah. I've been sailing
my whole life.
When I was 15,
my dad bought me my own boat.
What?
Your own boat?
What? What?
He was trying to cheer me up.
My pony was sick.
You know what
I was thinking?
What?
Nothing. I just like
to go like this.
Hey, Chandler,
what are you doing tonight?
Uh, Why?
Do you have a lecture?
No. Why?
Then free as a bird.
What's up?
My dad wanted to know
if you want to play
racquetball with us.
Wow, that's great.
Dad must really like you.
He doesn't ask
just anyone to play.
Yeah, and he didn't
really ask for you.
He asked for Chauncey.
I assumed he meant you.
Well, did-did you
correct him?
No. I-I thought
it'd be more fun this way.
That is so cool.
Maybe this is something
you could do every week.
Or you could sit with
him on the front porch
and make sure no one
steals the trash cans.
He does that
every week, too. Hmm.
Oh, just so you know,
y-you have to let him win.
He hates to lose.
Oh, no problem.
Maybe I'll play
with my left hand.
You're not a lefty?
Does anybody know me?
( sighs irately )
What's wrong, Phoebe?
I just went to my old
apartment to get you
the-the cookie recipe
and that stupid fire
burned it up.
No! Why didn't you
make a copy
and-and keep it
in a fireproof box
and keep it at least
a hundred yards
away from the original?
Because I'm normal.
But that was the one legacy
my grandmother left me
and I know you wanted it
as an engagement present.
What? We have to get you
an engagement present?
Don't worry
about it, Pheebs.
No one got me
an engagement present.
Okay, here.
I don't have the recipe, but...
Here, I wish you health
and happiness.
An old cookie?
See, this is what happens
when you don't register
for gifts.
See, no, I-I made a batch
and I froze it
and this is the only one left.
We can't accept this.
Why not?
Because it's gross.
No... wait.
I think I can figure out
the recipe from this cookie.
I do stuff like this
at work all the time.
Really?
Yeah. I think
I can do it.
Oh, yay!
Okay, Ross,
we owe you a present.
Two! I've been engaged twice.
Look at this clown.
Just 'cause he got
a bigger boat
he thinks he can take
up the whole river.
Get out of the way, jackass!
Who names their boat
Coast Guard, anyway, geez.
That is the Coast Guard.
What are they
doing out here?
Coast is all the
way over there.
Joe-Joey, just ignore
the boats, all right?
All right.
We're not finished
with our lesson yet.
I'm just going over the basic
points one more time. Ready?
Oh, come on, Rach, not again.
I got it, okay?
Let's start sailing,
and I want to go over there
where that boatload of girls is.
Yeah! Ho-ho!
Oh, okay. Is that
what you want to do?
Want to go over
and give a little shout out
to the old hot chicas, huh?
Okay. Let's do that, Sailor Joe.
Quick question, though.
What's this called?
Uh... boat rope?
Wrong.
How do you get
the main sail up?
Uh...
Rub it?
No.
What do you do if I say
we are coming about?
I'd say... come again?
No, no. I-I know this one,
I know this one. Uh...
( air horn honks )
Time's up. Now you're dead.
And deaf.
Okay, you just go on and make
your little jokey jokes
but if you do not know
what you are doing out at sea
you will die at sea.
Am I getting through
to you, sailor?!
Yes.
Don't just say yes.
This isn't a game.
Joey, you could really
get hurt out here.
Okay, so you want
to pay attention
or do you want to die?
I want to make a ship-to-shore
call to Chandler.
I-I definitely taste nutmeg.
You do?
You don't?
Huh. Well, that's
the difference
between a professional
and a layman.
Yeah. That and arrogance.
Hey.
Hey. How was sailing?
I don't want to talk about it.
Oh, you know, you could have
at least saved me
a whole cookie.
Both:
No, no, no, no!
Women are mean!
I can't believe that.
Well, now the only
thing that's left
of my grandmother's
legacy is... this crumb.
I wish you a long
and happy marriage.
Hey.
Hey. How was it?
Well, I had
a great time.
Um, Chauncey,
on the other hand...
I will tell the story.
It was going great.
I let him win.
We were bonding.
He even said
that I could call him Dad.
And what did he ask you
not to call him?
Daddy.
All right, look,
here's the story.
Well, we had just finished
playing racquetball
and we were going
to take a steam.
I walk into the steam room
and it's really steamy.
So I take off my glasses
and that's when it happened.
Guys?
Over here.
Have a seat, son.
Hey!
Oh, my God, Chandler.
I can't believe it.
I know.
You gave my father
a lap dance.
Why do they put
so much steam in there?
'Cause otherwise they'd have
to call it the... room room.
Why, okay?
Why?
Why did that have to happen?
Come on.
It's not that big a deal.
Not that big a deal?
There... there was touching
of things.
Chandler, I-I know you wanted
to bond with my dad
but did you really have to bond
to that part?
Listen, I'm sure that
Dad doesn't care.
He probably thought
this was really funny.
He'll be telling
this story for years.
I don't want him to tell
Oh, but he will.
( chuckles )
He still tells the story
about how Monica tried to escape
from fat camp.
I wasn't escaping.
Then how did you get caught
in the barbed wire?
I was trying to help out
a squirrel.
You were trying to eat it.
( phone rings )
If that is your
father calling
to tell this story
then the marriage is off.
Come on.
Hello?
I'm sorry. You have
the wrong number.
Okay. I'll call you later, Dad.
I love you.
All right. I'm off
to see your dad.
Whoa. Whoa!
Aren't you
a little overdressed?
( laughs )
Yeah. And-and you
better make sure
he tips you this time.
( laughing )
Oh, look. I figured
I would try to convince him
not to tell the story anymore
and I figured the best way
to do that was face-to-face.
And by face...
I don't mean his lap.
And by face,
I don't mean my ass.
Hey, are you getting
Monica and Chandler
an engagement present?
I don't know. You know,
they didn't get us anything.
Thank you.
Hey.
Well, hello.
So, when are we getting back
out on the water, matey?
Oh, uh...
Well, I don't know the boat way
to say this, but, uh... never.
Why not?
Because you're mean on the boat.
What? I was just
trying to teach you.
Well, lesson learned.
Rachel is mean.
Yup. Yup-yup-yup-yup-yup.
I remember when she took me
out on her dad's boat.
She wouldn't let me
help out at all.
Oh... excuse me.
I wanted you to help, but
you couldn't move your arms
because you were wearing
three life jackets.
You have to respect the sea.
Look, Joey, I'm sorry if-if
you thought that was mean
but I got to tell you something:
that was not mean, okay?
My father is mean.
He used to yell at me
all the time on the boat.
I mean, it was horrible.
I was just being
a really good teacher.
Does a good teacher say,
"Put down the beer, Pinhead"?
Well, does a good student
drink seven beers
during his first lesson?
Six and a half.
You knocked that last one
out of my hand, remember?
Yeah. I didn't want you
to get hit by the boom.
Well, it hit me anyway.
And it would have hurt
a lot less
if I'd have finished
that last beer.
All right. You know what?
I'm sorry.
I will try to tone it down,
and, uh... stop yelling.
You won't boss me around
anymore?
I won't boss you around.
And you'll be nice?
And I'll be nice.
And you'll be topless?
And... Joey!
You want me to learn?
Okay. Here's batch 22.
Oh, maybe these will taste
like your grandmother's.
This has a little bit
of orange peel, but no nutmeg.
Let's give it a shot.
Okay. Well...
I have not made
this many cookies
since I was in the ninth grade.
What was that for,
like, a bake sale?
No. Just a Friday night.
Mmm.
These are pretty good.
Yup. But not as good
as batch 17.
Which one was that?
The ones we had right after
you almost threw up.
Oh, yeah.
Batch 17 was good.
I did not like batch 16.
( voice croaks ):
I'm okay.
Are there any more
from the good batch?
'Cause we could just work
off of those.
Yeah... well, yeah,
I think there's one
from batch 17
left, uh...
It's batch 16.
16, people.
Get out of the way!
Okay, Joey, honey.
You're doing
really good.
All right, now.
I'm just going to need you
to step
to the port side.
Remember? Remember how we
talked about the port side?
Oh, yeah.
Right?
No.
It's left, sweetie,
but that's okay.
That's a tough one.
I wonder why
you don't just say left.
Okay. Go to the left.
( forced laughing )
( clears throat )
The left.
Huh?
( yells ):
Just sit over there!
Okay. Okay.
You're yelling again. See that?
No. No. No, no, no, no.
Very quiet, said with love,
no yelling.
Well, you know what?
Since I'm here,
I think I'm going to have me
a little beer
on the port side.
See what I did there?
Uh-huh.
( forced chuckle )
Okay, Joey,
we're luffing a little bit
so will you tighten up
the cunningham?
All right, whoa.
You just said a bunch of stuff
I don't know there.
Joey, come on!
We just went over this.
Oh. Oh-oh, you know that...
when we did that
was when that bird
was flying overhead
with the fish in his mouth.
Did you see it?
It was gross.
No! All right.
I did not see the bird.
I did not see the fish.
I did not see the piece
of Styrofoam
that was shaped
like Mike Tyson.
I did not because I was trying
to teach you how to sail a boat
which obviously is
an impossible thing to do.
All right. That's it.
You're yelling, and I don't see
you taking your top off. I quit!
Well...!
What do you mean, you quit?
You can't quit!
Why not?
Because you're
not finished yet
and I won't have it.
Greens do not quit.
"Greens"?
I'm a Tribbiani,
and Tribbianis quit.
Oh, my God! Wait!
Did I... did I...
I just said, "Greens don't
quit," didn't I?
Did I just say,
"Greens don't quit?!"
Yes. Yes.
Oh, my God.
You did, and you're
still yelling at me.
No. No, no.
I'm not yelling at you.
I'm just yelling near you.
Oh, God, Joey!
Oh, I'm my father.
Oh, my God!
This is horrible!
I've been trying so hard
not to be my mother
I did not see this coming.
Oh, Joey...
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I just wanted you to learn.
Oh.
Hey... I did learn.
Really?
Yeah. Come on.
No.
Yeah. It's okay.
I know what a mainsail is.
Yeah.
Huh? I know... I know to duck
when the boom comes across.
I-I know port is right.
Left.
Damn it!
You know, I bet
it would actually make
my grandma really happy
to know that we're trying
to figure out her recipe.
I bet she's looking up at us,
and smiling right now.
Looking up?
Oh, yeah.
No, she was really nice to me,
but she's in hell for sure.
Well, I've tried everything.
I give up.
I guess I'm not going to be
the mom who makes the world's
best chocolate chip cookies.
I do make the best...
duck confit with broccoli rabe.
( voice breaks ):
Kids love that, right?
Oh, Pheeb, come on.
Isn't there any relative
that would have the recipe?
What about... what about
your sister?
Oh, no, no. No.
I made a promise to myself
that the next time I would talk
to Ursula is over my dead body.
And that's not happening
until October 15, 2032.
That's the day
you're going to die?
See? Darn it.
I've got shuffleboard that day.
That's what you think.
Well, what about friends
of your grandmother's?
Wouldn't they have the recipe?
Well, you know, I may...
I may have relatives
in France who would know.
My grandmother said
she got the recipe
from her grandmother,
Nestle Toulous.
What was her name?
Nestle Tollhouse?
Uh!
You Americans always butcher
the French language.
Phoebe, is this the recipe?
Yes!
Oh! Oh...
I cannot believe
that I just spent
the last two days trying
to figure out that recipe
and it was in my cupboard
the whole time.
I know!
You see, it is
stuff like this
which is why
you're burning in hell!
Chandler:
Just so you understand
I'd feel a lot more comfortable
if you didn't tell people
what happened, you know?
I'm a little... I'm a little
embarrassed about it.
I understand completely.
There's nothing more horrifying
than embarrassing yourself
in front of your in-laws.
As a matter of fact,
when I started dating Judy
I was unemployed,
and her father asked me
what I did for a living,
and I told him I was a lawyer.
What-what did you do
when they found out?
They never did.
If you ever see me giving them
legal advice, just nod along.
Shall we?
So... I guess
we wear swimsuits in here.
Well, Joey,
I hate to admit it
but your way of sailing
is a lot more fun.
Yup. Yup.
Hey, why don't you
give a pull on that rope?
Oh, we're not sailing.
Just pull on it.
All right.
Hey!
Huh?
Sandwiches!
What else?
( chuckles )
Here you go.
Thank you.
Oh, wow!
Oop....
What are you doing?
Sorry.
What... don't hold
it like that.
You're letting all
the good stuff fall out.
Oh. Oop.
Careful!
You're wasting
good pastrami!
( gasps )
Oh, my God!
I'm my dad!